Jume Brice

FRONTEND DEVELOPER | TEAM LEAD

https://github.com/Jumeb | https://jumeb.github.io/ | https://www.linkedin.com/in/jume-njah/PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Accomplished front-end developer with a proven track record of building highly responsive, high-performing platforms prioritizing user experience and minimizing third-party dependencies. Adept at guiding talented teams in applying atomic design principles to deliver pixel-perfect, accurate implementations within tight timelines. Combines technical expertise, strategic vision, and effective leadership to drive successful project outcomes.

AREA OF EXPERTISE

✓ NextJS	✓ ReactJS	✓ TypeScript	✓ CSS3
✓ GraphQL	Tailwind CSS	✓ HTML5	✓ Redux JS
✓ Enzyme	✓ Jest	✓ React-native	✓ Team-work

CAREER HIGHLIGHTS

Codebase optimization: Successfully minimized up to 60% of third-party dependencies for the GasVisor mobile application, resulting in a 30% enhancement in user experience.

Efficient execution: Demonstrated a history of achieving a 98% pixel-perfect implementation of UI designs from the UI/UX department, utilizing minimal third-party packages, and driving a 30% increase in the deployment of new features.

Teamwork: 4+ years in team environments including 1.5+ years leading frontend development teams, resulted in a 20% increase in new feature releases by streamlining highly responsive implementations.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Chief of Engineering, Camsol Technologies UG, | AUG 2023 - Present

In this leadership role, I assisted in managing a 20 million euro portfolio consisting of two projects: one mobile and one web.

- Managed the implementation of the web platform's Calendar scheduler, resulting in a 10% increase in user growth and a 5% reduction in package dependency.
- Led the mobile team in implementing Redux for state management, resulting in a 50% code reduction and 40% efficiency increase.
- Guiding team in implementing design details from Figma for improved collaboration and development efficiency.

Lead Frontend developer, Camsol Technologies UG, | DEC 2022 - AUG 2023

Led team growth initiatives and spearheaded a small project that scaled to a multimillion-dollar venture.

- Partnered with the Product Owner to restructure the GasVisor mobile app codebase, aligning it with atomic design principles and improving code navigation by 70%.
- Implemented GitHub actions for automated Android APK generation and managed iOS TestFlight builds, enhancing platform-specific styling in the codebase.
- Enhanced GitHub workflows with branching strategies, automated checks, and streamlined deployments, resulting in a 28% boost in team velocity.

Frontend Developer, Camsol Technologies UG, | MARCH 2022 - DEC 2022

Joined as an entry-level position in a startup, learning the company's structure and seeking mentorship for career advancement in tech.

- Developed a mobile app for Romis using React Native, Contentful with GraphQL, and modern design patterns, enhancing their online purchase and financial record management.
- Adeptly troubleshooted known and unknown codebase issues, consistently delivering 5 integrated screens per week..
- Engaged in client discussions and strategic planning.
- Maintained this application and delivered on client request until the contract was over which led to me being recognized and given better opportunities.

EDUCATION

Bachelor in Engineering, University of Buea, Faculty of Engineering and Technolgy | SEPT 2017 - AUG 2021

TECHNICAL PROFICIENCIES

- **Proficient:** React, NextJS, CSS3, SASS, SCSS, TailwindCSS, React Native, JavaScript, TypeScript, Problem-Solving.
- Familiar with: NodeJS & Express, MongoDB, Directus, Heroku, Vercel, Docker
- Tools: VScode, Jira, Bitbucket, GitHub, Postman, MongoDB Compass, GitHub actions. Xcode

PROJECTS

Flavours Since AUG 2023 (Email: tester@gmail.com, Password: Qwerty1234)

A B2B/B2C platform connecting aspiring chefs in pastries or meals with food consumers.

- Implementing front-end solutions to simplify management and financial record-keeping for aspiring chefs.
- Developing REST APIs for CRUD operations requested by the front end, utilizing Express and MongoDB.